A Guide to the Daughters of Zelophehad (Chesterfield County, Va.) records, 1998-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Daughters of Zelophehad (Chesterfield County, Va.) records, 1998-2014
Library of Virginia
53432
2.7 cubic feet (6 boxes).
Daughters of Zelophehad (Chesterfield County, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift fo Paula Owens Parker, North Chesterfield, Virginia.
Historical Information
The Daughters of Zelophehad (DOZ) was a nonprofit organization out of Chesterfield Virginia founded by Rev. Dr. Paula Owens Parker. DOZ was a transitional housing program for mothers and children in crisis which allowed a mother and her children to stay in the program and housed for up to 2 years.
Scope and Content
Records, 1998-2014, of the Daughters of Zelophehad located in Chesterfield County, Virginia, containing documentation for the organization that highlights their efforts to help single mothers and their children through the organization's transitional housing program. Includes meeting minutes, correspondence, newspaper articles, and promotional materials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I: Administration/Organizational Functions
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Promotional Materials
Series IV: Curriculum
Series V: Programs and Events
Series VI: Newpaper articles/Media Coverage
Series VII: Photographs
Series VIII: Community Resources
Series IX: Miscellaneous
Contents List
- Administration/Organizational Functions, 3 boxes (Box 1-3)
  Administration/Organizational Functions, contains documents on the organizational functions including meeting minutes and agendas, handbooks, financial documents, grant applications, and information on the Board and residents of the program.
  - Daughters of Zelophehad summary (Box 1, Folder 0)
  - Meetings, 22 folders (Box 1, Folder 1-22)
    - Meetings2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - MeetingsJanuary-April 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - MeetingsMay-July 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - MeetingsAugust-September 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - MeetingsOctober 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - MeetingsNovember-December 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - MeetingsJanuary-February 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - MeetingsMarch-May 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - MeetingsAugust-December 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - MeetingsFebruary-April 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - MeetingsMay-June 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - MeetingsSeptember-November 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - MeetingsJanuary-February 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - MeetingsMarch 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - MeetingsApril-June 2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - MeetingsAugust-September 2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - MeetingsOctober-December 2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - MeetingsJanuary-March 2010 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - MeetingsApril-June 2010 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - MeetingsJuly-September 2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - MeetingsOctober-November 2010 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Meetings2011-2012 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Handbooks and Manuals, 9 folders (Box 1, Folder 23-31)
    - Articles of Incorporation and Bylaws16 January 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Policies and Procedures ManualJune 2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Dill House Program Handbook2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Employee Handbook2008 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - St. Barnabas and Dill House Program Handbook2009 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Financial Procedures Manual16 April 2009. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Board Members Manual (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Strategic Planning Documents (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Website Outlines (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Financial Documents, 17 folders (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
    - Financial Trend Analysis1999-2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Financial Statements and Independent Auditors Report31 December 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - DOZ Financial Assessment2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Financial Documents2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Budgets2005-2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Financial DocumentsJanuary-February 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Financial DocumentsMarch-August 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Financial DocumentsOctober-December 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Financial DocumentsMarch-November 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Financial DocumentsAugust-November 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Printing Needs for DOZ2008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Financial DocumentsJanuary-August 2008 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Financial DocumentsDecember 2008 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Donor Reports2008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Financial DocumentsJanuary-August 2009 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Financial DocumentsSeptember-December 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Financial DocumntsJanuary-September 2010 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Grant Funding, 9 folders (Box 2, Folder 18-26)
    - Grant letters and applications1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Grant Overview1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Grant letters and applications2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Grant letters and applications2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Grant charts2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Grant letters and applications2007 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Grant letters and applications2008-2012 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Grant Monthly Status Report (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Foundation Prospect List (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Board Members and Staff, 19 folders (Box 2, Folder 27-45)
    - Board Members Manual1998-2010 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Board Members Manual2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Board Members by Class2007-2012 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - DOZ Board Documents (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - DOZ Board Place Cards (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - DOZ StaffMay 2006 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - DOZ STaff Documents (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Tamara W. Clements (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Margaret Nimmo Crowe (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Tiffany Hall (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Margaret Lucas Jacobs (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Veronica Flemming Jemmott (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Dorothy Kuffler (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Deborah Little-Bowser (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Paula Owens Parker (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Michelle L. Roberts (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Suzanne Roski (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Consuelo Staton (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Denise Thomas-Brown (Staff) (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Daughters/Residents, 5 folders (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
    - Resident Statistics1999-2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Applications for 2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cara Cheatham (Daughter/Resident) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Shirley Ofori-Twumasi (Daugher/Resident) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Daughters/Residents Documents (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Papers, 4 folders (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
    - Calendars (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Dill and Barnabas House Renovations2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - DOZ Organizational Charts (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Thoughts on DOZ Remaining As Is (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1 box (Box 3)
  Correspondence contains a collection of emails, letters, invitations, and contracts with DOZ members and associates.
  - Emails, 15 folders (Box 3, Folder 10-24)
    - EmailsJune-November 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - EmailsFeburary-June 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - EmailsJuly 2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - EmailsAugust 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - EmailsSeptember-November 2005 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - EmailsJanuary-November 2006 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - EmailsMay-November 2007 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - EmailsJanuary-April 2008 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - EmailsJuly 2008 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - EmailsJanuary-February 2009 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - EmailsMarch-December 2009 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - EmailsJanuary 2010 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - EmailsFebruary-May 2010 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - EmailsJuly-September 2010 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - EmailsOctober-December 2010 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Letters, 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Letters2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Letters2009-2011 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Invitations, 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - InvitationsOctober 2007-September 2008 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Contracts, 6 folders (Box 3, Folder 28-33)
    - Commonwealth of Virginia Campaign Electronic AgreementApril 2004 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Unanimous Consent of Directors11 March 2005 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Purchase AgreementAugust 2005 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Board resolution to update bank account23 January 2006 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Crossroads Art Center Facility Use Contract1 May 2009 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Agreement to retain the services of accounting and tax resources29 December 2009 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - General Papers, 5 folders (Box 3, Folder 34-38)
    - Designs by Lucinda (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - DOZ letter and envelope templates (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - General envelopes (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Info to Dorothy from Rose Lane, March 28 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Band Together (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Promotional Materials, 1 box (Box 4)
  Promotional materials contains materials to garner funds for the organization and distribute information on current affairs.
  - The Promise newsletter, 4 folders (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - The Promise newsletter2002-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Promise newsletterSpring 2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Promise newsletter2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Promise newsletterFall 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising Materials, 11 folders (Box 4, Folder 5-15)
    - Letters for subscribers2005-2009 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters for subscribers (undated) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Complete lists of low hanging fruit fundraising ideas16 February 2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Church Tally4 November 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Wish lists2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Brochures (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Calendars (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - DOZ Information Packets (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - DOZ Organization Information Cards (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - DOZ Program and Contribution Packets (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Transitional Housing Cost Analysis (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Curriculum, 2 boxes (Box 4-5)
  Curriculum contains educational resources for both staff and residents including prayers, guidebooks, workshops, and worksheets.
  - DOZ Educational Resources (Board/Staff), 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
    - Educational Resources (Board/Staff) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Spirituality of Fundraising (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - DOZ Educational Resources (Residents), 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Educational Resources (Residents) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Prayers, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Prayers (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scripts, 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Scripts (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Workshops and Counseling, 7 folders (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
    - Healing from the Inside Out2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Healing from the Inside Out2008 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Healing from the Inside Out2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Healing from the Inside Out2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Creating a Nurturing Environment-Amy J. Harris (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Light of the World Prayer/Counseling Ministies (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Very Reverend Sandra (Sandi) B. Kerner (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Programs and Events, 1 box (Box 5)
  Programs and events contains information on DOZ programs and events held throughout the years including celebrations and fundraising events such as Chairs to Cherish, DOZ 10th Anniversary, and Coffee & Tea with the Daughters of Z.
  - Events, 12 folders (Box 5, Folder 8-19)
    - DOZ MilestonesDecember 1997-January 2001 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Programs1999-2009 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Chairs for Children14 October 2003 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Daughers Dinner Theater30 November 2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Chairs for Children23 October 2004 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - DOZ Retreat2005-2012 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Flyers2005-2008 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Dill House Blessing11 June 2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - DOZ Yard Sale19 August 2006 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Chairs to Cherish2 November 2006 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Long Walk to Freedom8 December 2007 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - DOZ 10th Anniversary13 November 2008 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chairs to Cherish2008, 7 folders (Box 5, Folder 20-26)
    - Artists (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Auction items and donations (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Meetings (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Planning Documents (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Website (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Events, 3 folders (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
    - Coffee and Tea with the Daughters of Z27 September 2009 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Traditional Moravian Candlelight Lovefeast (December 11) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Save the date list (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Newspaper Articles/Media Coverage, 1 box (Box 6)
  Media coverage Includes local media coverage of DOZ as well as other newspaper clippings stored by DOZ.
  - Government: you pray, we don't pay6 July 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Daughters of Zelophehad opens transitional home for women ex-offenders1 June 2006 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - House of Healing29 October 2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Women AidDecember 2006 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Power of Seven7 April 2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Charities trying mergers to improve bottom line11 November 2007 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Women Helping WomenDecember 2007 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bottom line: we can solve this problem13 January 2008 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Back on her feet, mother joins boardSpring/Summer 2008 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Colorful pins make statement, help Bethlehem Center30 May 2008 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Metropolitian Business League: Celebrating Black Business Month21 August 2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The faces of the county's homeless27 August 2008 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lewis Ginter Presents Chairs to CherishNovember 2008 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Faces of Hope Quarterly, volume I, Issue I26 January 2009 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - GPPC News17 July 2009 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A boost for hard-pressed groups14 December 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Photographs, 1 box (Box 6)
  Photographs includes personal photos and photo CDs of DOZ families, houses, and events.
  - Photos, 5 folders (Box 6, Folder 17-21)
    - St. Barnabas House Dedication2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - DOZ 10th Anniversary8 December 2007 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Chairs for Auction - Chairs to Cherish 200813 November 2008 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - DOZ Logo and Pin Designs (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - St. Barnabas House and Dill House's New Look! (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Photo CDs, 1 folder (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Photo CDs (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Community Resources, 1 box (Box 6)
  Community resources includes materials from various local community businesses and organizations.
  - Community Resources (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous, 1 box (Box 6)
  Miscellaneous contains various CD-Roms, state government documents, and handwritten notes.
  - CD-Roms (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - General Papers (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - State Government Documents1998-2012 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Handwritten Notes2007-2010 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Handwritten Notes (Undated) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Crochet Hook (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Wawa Card (Box 6, Folder 30)